Enas Fares

- Turgut özal MAH, Esenyurt, İstanbul Turkey +905318982895
- enasfares.b@gmail.com
 www.linkedin.com/in/enas-fares

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Software developer with fundamental knowledge of software design, developing database applications as well as administering database and information systems and testing, analyzing qualitative and quantitative data conducted an evaluation of organization's workflows.

Skilled in SQL, problem-solving, researching, collaborating, proficient, and committed. Flexible to try new stuff. I tend to keep the project on track to provide a much-needed better user experience and keep me motivated to learn about new technologies and new ways to improve our development results, with high capabilities in system analysis.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ICT Teacher

SEP 2021 - Currently

Levant International School, Istanbul - Turkey

- Plan, prepare and deliver daily lesson plans and instructional materials, excellent organization and time management skills.
- Work collaboratively with teachers, students, and staff, high sense of responsibility and flexibility.
- Preparing the child in the primary stage to know the general basics of the computer, in addition to learning robotics and working on Scratch.
- in the middle stage, teaching the meaning of database and applying using Access and Excel and learning the basics of networking, communication tools, multimedia, and design.
- In the high stage, we start the development of the basics as a front-end starting with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript then we move to the back-end learning all the details of python, in addition, to teaching the basics of image design as Photoshop.

Quality Assurance

NOV 2018 – AUG 2021

Alobathani Group, Istanbul - Turkey

- Manually tested the web application and performed sanity, exploratory, functional, and regression testing to ensure the quality of the product, performed.
- Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills with a talent for testing and analytic problem-solving and debugging skills.
- Monitor and maintain the global client assessment system and assisted with implementing and maintaining all compliance, and planning related to quality assurance.
- Assisted with documenting and communicating internal audit conclusions.
- Experience with JIRA Software for Test Planning.

Enas Fares Page 2 of 2

Technical Support Department

NOV 2015 – JAN 2017

Syriatel Mobile Telecom, Damascus - Syria

 Writing and optimizing complex queries SQL, PL/SQL, and programs required to retrieve data for special and recursive requests to manipulate and extract data from SQL Server.

- Creating indexes on tables to improve the performance and hide the actual tables and eliminate the complexity of the large queries.
- Coordinating with the design team to provide them with the necessary stored procedures and packages and the necessary insight into the data.
- Analyze the problem and translate it into a technical issue that should be solved and communicate with customers and be able the absorb their dissatisfaction and aid them to maintain the belief in Syriatel as the leading GSM provider in Syria.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering - Software Engineering Arab International University, Damascus – Syria	2015
Master SQL For Data Science Certificate Udemy	2021
Foundations of Agile Software Certificate Udemy	2021
Software Testing Simple (Software Quality Assurance QA) Udemy	2019
Course in ASP.NET & Android Certificate SCC-ITC	2014

LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Professional)
- Turkish (Intermediate)

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request